Diversity and Inclusion, Office of; Records ua370
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Office of Diversity and Inclusion Records
1970-2017
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
State University of New York at Albany. Office of Diversity and Inclusion
ua370
16.30 cubic ft.
Records of the Office of Diversity and Inclusion and its predecessors. Materials include administrative correspondence, committee and task force meeting materials, planning documentation, and assorted reports, all relating to issues of diversity, inclusion, equal employment, and discrimination.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
Acquisition Information
All items in this collection were transferred to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives.
Historical Note
The Office was formed in 1971 due to the establishment of an Affirmative Action Program on campus. It was initially part of the Office of Personnel and led by Leon J. Calhoun. As the responsibilities of this office expanded it became its own entity and was known as the Office of Equal Employment Opportunity. The office expanded through Title IX and Section 504 legislation that had recently been signed into law. These included the creation of sports teams for female students and addressed the treatment of students with disabilities on campus. It later became known as the Affirmative Action Office and overseen by Gloria DeSole who also worked in the Task Force for Women's Safety at the same time. In 2003 it became known as the Office of Diversity and Affirmative Action before becoming the Office of Diversity and Inclusion in 2010. The role of this is to provide diversity-related training and resources, address discrimination and harassment complaints, enforcement and support of legislation such as Section 504. One of their greatest current responsibilites is oversight on the recruiting and hiring processes in all aspects of the University. This includes approval of advertisements for positions and potential candidates for interviews.
Scope and Contents
This collection includes affirmative action and recruitment plans; student surveys; workforce analysis documents; conference materials; daily correspondence (1974-1986); Federal compliance reports (1971); task force and committee materials including: the Women's Concerns Committee (1978-2000), the Task Force on Women's Safety, the Black Action Coalition, and others. Topics covered include: Section 504 (which addresses disability discrimination), Title IX, and equal employment.
There is a single series dedicated to Women's Studies 399: Classism, Racism, and Sexism, a class taught by staff of the Affirmative Action Office in 1977. Finally, there is also a series containing Affirmative Action Plans produced by the Research Foundation.
Arrangement of the Collection
Collection is arranged into nine distinct series based on subject. Original order is maintained within each series.
Women; Affirmative action programs; Affirmative action programs in education; Discrimination in employment; Administrative records; Administrative reports; Minutes (administrative records); State University of New York at Albany
- Office of Equal Employment Opportunity, 1973-1974; 4.0 cubic ft.
  Arrangement
  Series is arranged in its original order.
  Scope and Contents
  Series is made up of papers from the first iteration of the office as its own entity. Contains memos, correspondence, meeting minutes, and plans for the future of the Equal Employment Oppurtunity Office.
  - Personnel Associate Position Filled by S. Stronger, 1973 January 3 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Salary Equalization Data, 1972-1975 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Personnel Associate (EEO Women) Filled by Dolores B. Schmidt, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Federal Compliance Report, 1971 March 26 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Federal Compliance Report, 1970-1974 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Federal Compliance Report, 1971 March 26 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Ethnic Survey, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - EEO Conference for Administrators, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - EEO Advisory Committee, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - EEO Compliance Review, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Survey on Religion and National Origin, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Title IX Institutional Self-evaluation State University of New York at Albany, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Census Reports, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Census Reports, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Census Reports, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Census Reports, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Affirmative Action Program General, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Affirmative Action Program General, 1972-1974 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Census Reports, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Affirmative Action Progress Review, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Steno Trainee Program, 1971-1973 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Review and Analysis of Personnel Activities (RAPA), 1974 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Affirmative Action Office, 1970-1972 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Affirmative Action Office, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Affirmative Action Office, 1973-1975 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Affirmative Action Office, 1976-1980 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Affirmative Action Office, 1981-1984 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Workforce Analysis, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Work Development Program for High School Students, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Training Programs, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Summary of Affirmative Action Plan, Undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - SUNY EEO Officers, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Student Affairs, 1972 August 2 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Steno Trainee Program Evaluation Reports, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Steno Trainee Program, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Sponsored Funds/ Research Foundation, 1971-1973 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Research Foundation/ Sponsored Funds, 1971 November 8-1972 January 6 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Requirement Memo's, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Recruitment, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Recruitment, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Reclassification Committee, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Poverty Research and Training Program, 1974 September 5 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Posting Procedures, 1971 April 2; 1974 March 5 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Policy Statements, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Organization Chart, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Open Recruitment, 1972 February 7 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Open House, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Newsletter, 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Older Returning Student, 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Typing Older Returning Students Newsletter, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Office for Civil Rights (U.S), 1973 September 25 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Office of Civil Rights (HEW), 1972 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Non-Teaching Professionals, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Jobs for the Veterans, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Job Descriptions, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Guidelines for AA in All Departments, Undated (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - A Guide for the Development of AA Programs (SUNY), 1971 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - General, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Affirmative Action Budget (86785), 1971 July-1974 December (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Affirmative Action Advisory Committee, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Affirmative Action Advisory Committee, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Affirmative Action Advisory Committee, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Affirmative Action Advisory Committee Dr. Nathan Wright. Chairman (EEOAC), 1971 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Affirmative Action Advisory Committee, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Office of Diversity and Inclusion: Model Affirmative Action Plan, 1971-1973 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Older Women Student, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Mailing Lists, Undated (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Florynce Kennedy Week, 1974 October 21 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - General, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Faculty Wives, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Child Care, 1973 July 11 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Affirmative Action/Women, 1971-1973 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Status of Women/ Institutional Research, 1969; 1971-1973 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Status of Women General, 1971-1974 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Options for Women III Mechanicville, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Options for Women, 1974; Undated (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Women's Caucus, 1971-1974 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - CWRS Letters to Chancellor, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - CWR/SUNY, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - CWR Letters to Mrs. Moore, Chairperson. Board of Trustees, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Affirmative Action Program, 1972-1974 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Office of Equal Employment Opportunity, 1971-1973 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Office of Diversity and Inclusion: Minority and Women Recruiting Sources, 1972 July 27 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Special Projects Affirmative Action Folder #2, 1971-1976 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Equal Employment Committee, 1972-1973 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Office of Diversity and Inclusion Minutes of November 12, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Equal Employment Opportunity Advisory Committee Members, 1973 August 24 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Office of Diversity and Inclusion: Reports on the Status of Women, 1971; 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Office of Diversity and Inclusion: Grievance Procedure for Review, 1971-1974; 1976-1978 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - SUNY -A Affirmative Action Plan, 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Office of Diversity and Inclusion: Personnel Recruitment and Appointment Policy, 1972 June 7 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Affirmative Action Committee for Equitable Employment of Minorities, 1970-1971 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Office of Diversity and Inclusion: Equal Employment Opportunity in SUNY, 1972; 1974; 1976 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - A Plan for Equal Employment Opportunity in State University of New York, 1972 December 1 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Office of Diversity and Inclusion: Work Force Analysis, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Affirmative Action, 1971-1973 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Affirmative Action, 1972-1973 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Office of Equal Employment Opportunity (EEO), 1972; 1974 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Affirmative Action Plan, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Affirmative Action, 1971-1973 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Office of Diversity and Inclusion: Plan for Equal Employment Opportunity in SUNY, 1972 December 1 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Office of Diversity and Inclusion: Affirmative Action Plan, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Office of Diversity and Inclusion: Title IX Study on Sexism, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Office of Diversity and Inclusion: Where are the Women?, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Presidents Office, 1973-1977 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Personnel - General, 1973-1974; 1976-1979 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Office of Diversity and Inclusion: Request to Fill Vacancy, 1977 April 1-1978 November 30 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Institutional Research, 1973-1977 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Space for AAO, 1977; 1979 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Plant Department, 1973-1978 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Finance and Business, 1977-1979 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Office of Diversity and Inclusion: Office of Civil Rights Memorandum, 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Affirmative Action: Equal Opportunity Employment, 1971; 1973 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Affirmative Action Sub-Committee: Ethnic Survey File, 1969; 1971-1972; Undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Fair Employment Practices Committee, 1971 March 9; 1973 June 14 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Faculty Student Association, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Faculty & Staff Administration, 1970-1972 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Executive Order 11246, Undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Ethnic Survey Graduate Assistants, 1970-1971 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Ethnic Survey Graduate Assistants, 1970-1971 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Ethnic Survey, 1967-1968; 1973-1975 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Ethnic Survey, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Ethnic Survey, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Ethnic Survey Graduate Assistants, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Ethnic Classifications, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Employment Status Reports, 1971-1973 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Employment/ Minorities/ Women, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Office of Equal Employment Opportunity- Affirmative Action Plan, 1973 October (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Office of Equal Employment Opportunity, 1970-1973; 1975 July 9 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - EEO for Women Committee, 1971-1972 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - EEO in SUNY, 1971 November 17; 1972 July 13 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - EEO Plan, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - EEO Guides, 1971-1973 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - EEO Act, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Educational Policies Council, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Office of Equal Employment Opportunity- Affirmative Action Plan, 1973 October (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Division of Human Rights, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Conferences, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Conferences, 1973-1974 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Commitments to A.A, 1971-1972; 1974 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Career Counseling Advisory Board, 1974-1975 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - An Affirmative Action Plan-Examples, Undated (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Final Reports Career Counseling, 1974-1975 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Affirmative Action Program, 1972 March 9 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Affirmative Action Program, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Career Counseling/OLG Proposals, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Office of Diversity and Inclusion: Career Counseling/ General, 1974-1975 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Affirmative Action Plan, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Affirmative Action- Anti- Defamation League, 1971-1973 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - American Jewish Congress, 1972 September 21 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Affirmative Action Reports, 1972-1973; Undated (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Affirmative Action/Impact, 1971-1972 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Affirmative Action Compliance, 1971; 1973 (Box 4, Folder 41)
- Workforce Analysis, 1975-1980; 1.66 cubic ft.
  This series holds materials from the analysis of the faculty and staff of the University, breaking the population down by the gender and race of each member.
  - Affirmative Action Plan, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Workforce Analysis Received, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Affirmative Action Plan, 1974; Undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Workforce Analysis Received, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Revised Affirmative action Plan, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - AAP: Harvey Kahalas Dean's Office School of Business, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Accounting, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Management Source, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Marketing, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Law, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Finance, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - AAP: Robert Koff Dean's Office School of Education, 1984-1985; Undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Foundation of Education, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Child Study Research Center, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Teacher's Education, 1983; 1985 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Counseling Psychology, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Education Administration, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Program Development & Ed, 1984 October 12 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Reading, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Field Service CTR/CASDA, Undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Education Research & Service Center, Undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Education Psychology & Statistic, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - School Psychology, 1984 November 1 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - AAP: Richard Halsey Dean's Office Library & Info. Science, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - AAP: Paul Wallace Dean's Office College of Humanities, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Art, 1984 November 5 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Theatre, 1984 November 28 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Slavic Languages, 1984 December 13 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Philosophy, 1984 December 17 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Rhetoric & Communication, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Performing Art Center, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Music, 1983; 1985 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Judaic Studies, 1984 November 14 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Hispanic & Italian, 1983; 1984 December 18 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - German, 1984 November 29 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - French, 1984 December 24 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - English, 1984 December 20 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Classics, 1984 December 5 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Chinese, 1984 November 6 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Women Studies Program, 1985 January 29 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - AAP: Daniel Wulff Dean's Office Science & Mathematics, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Biological Science, 1981-1983 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Neuro Biological Research, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Chemistry, 1983; Undated (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Geological Science, 1981-1983 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Mathematics, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Physics, 1983-1985 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Atmospheric Science, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - AAP: John Webb Dean's Office Social & Behavior Sciences, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Psychology, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Sociology, 1984 November 29 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Puerto Rican Studies, 1984 November 28 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - History, 1984 November 29 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Geography, 1984 November 15 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Anthropology, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - African Afro-American Studies, Undated (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Economics, 1984 October 30 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - AAP: David Anderson Dean's Office GSPA, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Comparative Development Study Center (CDSC), 1985 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Center for Women and Government, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Public Administration, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Public Executive Development Project, Undated (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Political Science, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - AAP: Stuart Kirk Dean's Office School of Social Welfare, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - AAP: Richard Dressner Dean's Office Divison of Continuing Studies, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - President's Office Summary Sheet, Undated (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - President's Office, Undated (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Vice President Ramaley Academic Affairs, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Computing Center, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Finance & Business, 1980; Undated (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Vice President's Office, Undated (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Office of Student Accounts, Undated (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Space Management, Undated (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Security, Undated (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Purchasing, Undated (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Plant, Undated (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - Payroll, Undated (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Personnel, Undated (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - Internet Audit, Undated (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - Equipment Inventory Control, Undated (Box 1, Folder 80)
  - Controller, Undated (Box 1, Folder 81)
  - Bursar, Undated (Box 1, Folder 82)
  - Budget, Undated (Box 1, Folder 83)
  - Affirmative Action, Undated (Box 1, Folder 84)
  - Accounting: Accounts Payable, Undated (Box 1, Folder 85)
  - University Affairs, Undated (Box 1, Folder 86)
  - Office of VP, Undated (Box 1, Folder 87)
  - Career Planning & Placement, Undated (Box 1, Folder 88)
  - Community Relations/News Bureau, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 89)
  - Counseling, Undated (Box 1, Folder 90)
  - Dean's Office Student Affairs, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 91)
  - Financial Aids, Undated (Box 1, Folder 92)
  - Governance, Undated (Box 1, Folder 93)
  - Physical Education, Undated (Box 1, Folder 94)
  - Residence Halls Administration, Undated (Box 1, Folder 95)
  - Student Activities, Undated (Box 1, Folder 96)
  - Student Health Service, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 97)
  - Student Life, Undated (Box 1, Folder 98)
  - Student Union, Undated (Box 1, Folder 99)
  - Revised Affirmative Action Plan, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 100)
  - Minority Recruitment Task Force, 1975-1979; Undated (Box 1, Folder 101)
  - Affirmative Action Plan and Workforce Analysis Forms, 1979; Undated (Box 1, Folder 102)
  - GSPA, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 103)
  - Employee Numbers, 1979; Undated (Box 1, Folder 104)
  - Manuals and Guides, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 105)
  - Affirmative Plan, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 106)
  - AAP continued, 1978-1979; Undated (Box 1, Folder 107)
  - Workforce Analysis, 1978; 1983; Undated (Box 1, Folder 108)
  - Workforce Figures, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 109)
  - Workforce Analysis, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 110)
  - Affirmative action Plan Drafts, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Workforce Analysis, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Affirmative Action Office: Workforce Analysis Part II, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Affirmative Action Office: Workforce Analysis Part II, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Affirmative Action Office: Workforce Analysis Part II, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Affirmative Action Office, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - The Forum, 1980-1981 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Forum, 1981-1982 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Recruitment of Minorities, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Student Activities & Concerns, Undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Affirmative Action Plan Goals and Timetables, Undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Goals and Time Tables for AAP, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Day Files, 1974-1986; 1.0 cubic ft.
  The series is in its original order.
  This series holds daily office papers filed by Gloria DeSole and Rosemary Kilkenny Sabai who were directors of the Affirmative Action Office during this period. It includes office memos, correspondence within the University and without, and meeting minutes. These all hold information on office work such as the workforce analysis of the campus, hiring waiver requests, and dealings with Section 504 and Title IX.
  - Day File, 1974 January-1974 April 4 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Day File, 1974 April 4-1974 August 29 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Day File, 1974 September 3-1974 December 20 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Day File, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Day File, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Day File, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Day File, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Day File, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Day File, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Day File, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Day File, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Day File Part I, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Day File Part II, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Recruitment Plans, 1973-1985; 1.66 cubic ft.
  The recruitment Plans series consists of reports on how each department at the University planned “to overcome underutilization of minorities and women” in their new hires process. The series also holds documents created by the Black Action Coalition and other minority and female employment support groups affecting change on the University Campus.
  - Waiver of Advertising, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Waivers, 1982-1985 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Recruitment Plan, School of Criminal Justice, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Rockefeller College of Public Affairs: Recruitment Plans, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Recruitment Plans: College of Mathematics and Science, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - School of Library and Information Sciences, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Academic Affairs Computing Center, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - School of Business: Recruitment Plans, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - General Studies: Recruitment Plans, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Academic Affairs: University Library, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - College of Humanities: Recruitment Plan, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - College of Social and Behavioral Sciences, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - School of education: Recruitment Plans, 1980-1982 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - AA Recruitment Plans, 1980-1982 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Women's Studies, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Black Action Coalition, 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Black Action Coalition, 1981-1985 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Black Action Coalition, Undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - A.F.L C.L.O, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - BAC Mailing List, 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - BAC Newsletter, 1979-1982 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - University News, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Black Action Coalition, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Black Caucus SUNY, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Ronnie Dysen, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Solidarity Committee, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Black Faculty + Administrators of the Capitol District, 1971-1978 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Black Librarians Daty Bank, 1973-1975 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Unscheduled Requests, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 15)